Austin Howard

Morristown, TN cnfishead@gmail.com 14233535034

Proactive junior software developer with a passion for code and solid background of superior performance in related roles. Demonstrating 4+ years of self-taught knowledge as well as professional development at defined institutions.

Willing to relocate: Anywhere

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

Work Experience

Unloader/Loader

Walmart DC - Midway, TN May 2016 to December 2020

May 2016 to Dec 2020

- Used ladders and pallet jacks to load and unload merchandise weighing up to 5000 pounds.
- Labeled packages and pallets to ensure efficient identification of items.
- Operated forklifts, lift gates and pallet jacks with focus on safety and efficiency.

Shift Manager

Shift Manager

McDonalds Corp - Clarksville, TN October 2013 to May 2015

Positioned staff in key areas throughout shift to Optimize department productivity.

- Enhanced operations and boosted efficiency through employee training, coaching, and creating work schedules and assignments.
- Upheld company standards and compliance requirements for operations and cleanliness of all areas.
- Cross-trained in every store role to maximize operational knowledge.
- Established ambitious goals for employees to promote achievement and surpass business targets.

Education

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

Southern New Hampshire University - Manchester, NH Present

Associate of Arts in Mathematics

Southeast Kentucky Community and Technical College - Cumberland, KY January 2016

Associate of Science in Mathematics

Southeast Kentucky Community and Technical College - Cumberland, KY

Skills

- Certified forklift operator
- NodeJS
- Bootstrap
- · Strong math skills
- Hazardous materials knowledge
- Java programming language
- HTLM
- Communication
- · Relationship building
- Expertise in Python Programming Language
- Expertise in JavaScript
- Excel spreadsheets
- APIs
- GitHub
- CSS
- HTML5
- Software Development
- Git
- User Interface (UI)
- Express.js
- templating
- ReactJS
- JSON
- REST
- MongoDB
- Debugging
- Responsive web design
- Web development
- Software deployment
- jQuery
- Research
- Analysis skills
- Software troubleshooting
- Back-end development
- MySQL
- XML

http://cnfishead.github.io

Certifications and Licenses

Forklift Certification

Assessments

Software developer fit — Proficient

January 2021

Measures the traits that are important for successful software developers

Full results: Proficient

Attention to detail — Highly Proficient

January 2021

Identifying differences in materials, following instructions, and detecting details among distracting

information

Full results: Highly Proficient

Search engine optimization — Highly Proficient

January 2021

Interpreting online website performance metrics and understanding search engine optimization tactics Full results: <u>Highly Proficient</u>

Verbal communication — Highly Proficient

January 2021

Speaking clearly, correctly, and concisely

Full results: Highly Proficient

Sales skills — Proficient

January 2021

Influencing and negotiating with customers

Full results: Proficient

Programming fundamentals — Proficient

January 2021

Designed by engineering managers and real-world employers, this test gives you hard data points to evaluate technical competency

Full results: Proficient

Java — Familiar

January 2021

Designed by engineering managers & real-world employers, this Java test evaluates general technical competency

Full results: Familiar

Customer focus & orientation — Highly Proficient

January 2021

Responding to customer situations with sensitivity

Full results: Highly Proficient

Customer service — Proficient

January 2021

Identifying and resolving common customer issues

Full results: Proficient

Indeed Assessments provides skills tests that are not indicative of a license or certification, or continued development in any professional field.